Leah: Debugging!
what exactly is meant by debugging?
Debugging is the process of
identifying and removing existing
and potential errors or ‘bugs’
in code and debugging and testing
are process which occur hand in hand.
Testing aims to identify what happens
when there are errors in the code.
Debugging aims to locate
and rectify mistakes.
Often tests are written to identify
bugs as the program is written.
One way to do this is
by writing unit tests.
So, what is a unit test?
Jack: A unit test is a way of testing
the smallest piece of code that can
be logically isolated in a system.
Smaller tests give a granular view
of how the code is performing and by
being small, a test can be run fast.
Specific tests are written to test whether
a unit is functioning as it should.
This then allows developers to write
a test script, which is essentially
a piece of code, separate to the main
program, that runs a specific test,
for each unit in the main program.
Each unit is tested to see if it runs
as expected based on criteria and
it then summarises this in a report.
Each time the program is updated, the
test script will be run to ensure that
all units are functioning correctly.
This helps to debug the whole
program as new units are added.
Leah: Now we have discussed
debugging let’s look at an
example of this using code.